Guide to the Richard Henry Pratt Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- General Correspondence and Official Papers, 1867-1924; Series I; (74 boxes)
  - OUTGOING LETTERS
    - Unbound letters, 13 items, 1921 Jul-Aug (Box 12, Folder 412)
    - Unbound letters, 16 items, 1921 Sep-Nov (Box 12, Folder 413)
    - Unbound letters, 14 items, 1921 Dec (Box 12, Folder 414)
    - Unbound letters, 14 items, 1922 Jan (Box 12, Folder 415)
    - Unbound letters, 12 items, 1922 Feb-Mar (Box 12, Folder 416)
    - Unbound letters, 10 items, 1922 Apr (Box 12, Folder 417)
    - Unbound letters, 19 items, 1922 May-Jun (Box 12, Folder 418)
    - Unbound letters, 17 items, 1922 Jul (Box 12, Folder 419)
    - Unbound letters, 14 items, 1922 Sep (Box 12, Folder 420)
    - Unbound letters, 9 items, 1922 Oct (Box 12, Folder 421)
    - Unbound letters, 18 items, 1922 Nov (Box 12, Folder 422)
    - Unbound letters, 7 items, 1922 Dec (Box 12, Folder 423)
    - Unbound letters, 16 items, 1923 Jan (Box 12, Folder 424)
    - Unbound letters, 23 items, 1923 Feb (Box 12, Folder 425)
    - Unbound letters, 10 items, 1923 Mar (Box 12, Folder 426)
    - Unbound letters, 10 items, 1923 Apr (Box 12, Folder 427)
    - Unbound letters, 13 items, 1923 May (Box 12, Folder 428)
    - Unbound letters, 23 items, 1923 Jun (Box 12, Folder 429)
    - Unbound letters, 12 items, 1923 Jul (Box 12, Folder 430)
    - Unbound letters, 13 items, 1923 Aug (Box 12, Folder 431)
    - Unbound letters, 19 items, 1923 Sep, Oct (Box 12, Folder 432)
    - Unbound letters, 16 items, 1923 Nov, Dec (Box 12, Folder 433)
    - Unbound letters, 2 items, 1924 (Box 12, Folder 434)
    - Unbound letters, 2 items (Box 12, Folder 435)
  - LETTERS OF OTHERS
    - Anderson, M. B. to Miss Mather, 1 item, 1879 (Box 13, Folder 436)
    - Armstrong, S. C. to E. D. Townsend, 1 item, 1878 (Box 13, Folder 437)
    - Armstrong, S. C. to Daniel and Mrs. Fox, 1 item, 1882 (Box 13, Folder 438)
    - Armstrong, S. C. to Miss Mather, 1 item, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 439)
    - Bailey, G. M. to S. C. Armstrong, 1 item, 1888 (Box 13, Folder 440)
    - Bakeless, O. H. to W. N. Hailman, 1 item, 1894 (Box 13, Folder 441)
    - Bard, T. R. to W. A. Jones, 1 item, 1902 (Box 13, Folder 442)
    - Biddle, E. W. and others to T. Roosevelt, 1 item, 1904 (Box 13, Folder 443)
    - Bishop, T. G. to Dewitt Hare, 1 item, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 444)
    - Bonnot, F. R. to E. A. Hayt, 1 item, 1878
    - Brunhouse, R. L. to E. A. Cutter, 4 items, 1933-34 (Box 13, Folder 445)
    - Burke, C. H. to E. A. Cutter, 1 item, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 446)
    - Caruthers, H. to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, 1 item, 1878 (Box 13, Folder 447)
    - Curtis, C. to J. C. Harper, 1 item, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 448)
    - Curtis C. to G. H. Powell, 1 item, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 449)
    - Cutter, E. A. to R. L. Brunhouse, 6 items, 1933-34, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 450)
    - Dortch, J. H. to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, 1 item, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 451)
    - Flagler, H. M. to Mrs. Russell Sage, 1 item, 1883 (Box 13, Folder 452)
    - Gansworth, H. E. to K. Taylor, 1 item, 1916 (Box 13, Folder 453)
    - Gansworth, H. E. to Mrs. E. P. Robitaille, 1 item, 1924 (Box 13, Folder 454)
    - Gibbs, J. W. to Miss Perit, 1 item, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 455)
    - Good Bear, P. to A. S. Ely, 1 item, 1894 (Box 13, Folder 456)
    - Hailman, W. N. to O. H. Bakeless, 2 items, 1894 (Box 13, Folder 457)
    - Harper, J. C. to H. P. Snyder, 1 item, 1920 (Box 13, Folder 458)
    - Harper, J. C. to C. Curtis, 1 item, 1920
    - Jones, W. A. to E. A. Hitchcock, 1 item, 1899 (Box 13, Folder 459)
    - Keogh, Mr. J. E. to J. Bakeless, 1 item, 1955 (Box 13, Folder 460)
    - Larocque, A. S. to Miss Perit, 1 item, [1879?] (Box 13, Folder 461)
    - Lyman, C. and Roosevelt, T. to B. Harrison, 1 item, 1893 (Box 13, Folder 462)
    - McCammon, J. K. to R. M. Henderson, 1 item, 1896 (Box 13, Folder 463)
    - McCauley, J. A. to J. B. Storer, 1 item, 1892 (Box 13, Folder 464)
    - McKee, [W. C.?] to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, 1 item, 1882 (Box 13, Folder 465)
    - McKenzie, F. A. to C. Montezuma, 1 item, 1913 (Box 13, Folder 466)
    - McKenzie, F. A. to A. G. Harper, 1 item, 1934
    - McKinley, W. to The Rev. C. C. McCabe, 1 item, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 467)
    - Mahon, T. M. to J. A. Lippincott, 1 item, 1894 (Box 13, Folder 468)
    - Mann, J. R. to C. Montezuma, 1 item, 1898 (Box 13, Folder 469)
    - Meritt, E. B. to E. A. Cutter, 1 item, 1928 (Box 13, Folder 470)
    - Montezuma, C. to T. J. Saul, 1 item, 1909 (Box 13, Folder 471)
    - Moorehead, W. K. to Delaware County Institute of Science, 1 item, 1910 (Box 13, Folder 472)
    - Nelson, K. to J. Flinn, 1 item, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 473)
    - Nelson, K. to H. Welsh, 1 item, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 474)
    - N. Calif. Indian Assoc. to E. A. Hitchcock, 1 item, 1904 (Box 13, Folder 475)
    - Plumb, P. B. to A. A. Hyde, 1 item, 1881 (Box 13, Folder 476)
    - Randall, S. J. to Miss Longstreth, 1 item, 1882 (Box 13, Folder 477)
    - Randlett, J. F. to the Commissioner of Indian Affairs, 1 item, 1903 (Box 13, Folder 478)
    - Rice, W. G. to K. Nelson, 1 item, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 479)
    - Schurz, Carl to G. McCrary, 1 item, 1880 (Box 13, Folder 480)
    - Sherman, J. S. to R. M. Henderson, 1 item, 1897 (Box 13, Folder 481)
    - Sim-po-quo-del to Kiowa and Comanche Friends, 1 item, 1877 (Box 13, Folder 482)
    - Snowden, A. L. to D. M. Fox, 1 item, 1882 (Box 13, Folder 483)
    - Society of American Indians to W. Wilson, 1 item, 1914 (Box 13, Folder 484)
    - Welsh, H. to unknown, 1 item, 1895 (Box 13, Folder 485)
    - Welsh, H. to K. Nelson, 1 item, 1897
    - Wickersham, J. to L. F. Paul, 1 item, 1921 (Box 13, Folder 486)
  - OFFICIAL PAPERS
    - Miscellaneous papers, 8 items, 1863-1870 (Box 14, Folder 487)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 10 items, 1873-74 (Box 14, Folder 488)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 4 items, 1875 Mar-Apr (Box 14, Folder 489)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 10 items, 1875 May (Box 14, Folder 490)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 15 items, 1875 Jun-Nov (Box 14, Folder 491)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 15 items, 1876 (Box 14, Folder 492)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 13 items, 1877 (Box 14, Folder 493)
    - Letterbook regarding Indian prisoners in Florida, 1 item, 1875-77 (Box 14, Folder 493a)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 15 items, 1878 (Box 14, Folder 494)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 10 items, 1879-80 (Box 14, Folder 495)
    - Miscellaneous papers, 17 items, 1897-1923, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 496)
    - General orders, 6 items, 1875-78, 1914 (Box 14, Folder 497)
    - Special orders, 12 items, 1863-69 (Box 14, Folder 498)
    - Special orders, 15 items, 1870-1904 (Box 14, Folder 499)
- Family Correspondence, 1862-1956; Series II; (4 boxes)
  Series II, Family Correspondence, is grouped into eight subseries, one for each of the following members of the Pratt Family: Nana Pratt Hawkins (daughter), Anna Laura Pratt (wife), Mason Delano Pratt (son), Richard Henry Pratt, R. H. Pratt, II (grandson), Sarah Pratt (granddaughter), Guy LeRoy Stevick (son-in-law), Marion Pratt Stevick (daughter). Within each subseries the correspondence is arranged alphabetically by the name of the author. Letters written by the eight family members are filed under the name of the recipient. All letters written by the family members are filed in their respective subseries, except those addressed to General Pratt. All letters written to Pratt are filed in the R. H. Pratt section under the name of the author.
  - NANA PRATT HAWKINS
    - Agnew, Mary N., 1 item, 1905 (Box 15, Folder 500)
    - Army War College, 7 items, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 501)
    - Bailey, Nick, 1 item, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 502)
    - Bakeless, John, 6 items, 1930-33, n.d.
    - Brunhouse, R. L., 3 items, 1934, 1939 (Box 15, Folder 503)
    - Cass Co. Historical Assoc., 1 item, 1930
    - Champney, Mrs. James W., 1 item, 1885 (Box 15, Folder 504)
    - Collier, John, 3 items, 1934-35
    - Cutter, Emma A., 7 items, 1934-38, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 505)
    - Davis, O. deForest, 2 items, 1920, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 506)
    - Dawes, Anna L., 1 item, 1937
    - de Tudo, Angela R., 1 item, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 507)
    - Eastman, Elaine Goodale, 15 items, 1933-38 (Box 15, Folder 508)
    - Foreman, Grant, 1 item, 1941 (Box 15, Folder 509)
    - Gansworth, Howard E., 2 items, 1934-35?
    - Thomas Gilcrease Foundation, 1 item, 1947 (Box 15, Folder 510)
    - The Hamilton Library, 2 items, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 511)
    - Hawkins, Edgar M., 1 item, 1929
    - Hayne, Cal, 1 item, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 512)
    - Houghton Mifflin Co., 1 item, 1951
    - Kahler, Herbert E., 3 items, 1936 (Box 15, Folder 513)
    - Library of Congress, Division of Manuscripts, 1 item, 1930
    - J. B. Lippincott Co., 5 items, 1940 (Box 15, Folder 514)
    - Little, Brown and Co., 1 item, 1951
    - McDonald, Nettie, 1 item, 1920 (Box 15, Folder 515)
    - McDougall, Susie, 1 item, 1920
    - Middleton, The Rev. C. S. H., 3 items, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 516)
    - Morgan, J. H., 1 item, 1924
    - Nat'l Cyclopedia of American Biography, 2 items, 1933 (Box 15, Folder 517)
    - Parker, Arthur C., 1 item, 1942 (Box 15, Folder 518)
    - Paul, Fanny G., 1 item, n.d.
    - Paul, Louis F., 2 items, 1921, 1924 (Box 15, Folder 519)
    - Priest, Loring B., 1 item, 1942
    - Pratt, Mason D., 16 items, 1933-44 (Box 15, Folder 520)
    - Pratt, Richard H., II, 3 items, 1936, 1943
    - Pratt, Richenda H., 3 items, 1902 (Box 15, Folder 521)
    - Pratt, Sarah Smith, 2 items, 1933-34
    - G. P. Putnam's Sons, 6 items, 1924, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 522)
    - Rogers, Will, 1 item, 1936
    - Sage, Margaret Olivia Slocum, 1 item, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 523)
    - Russell Sage Foundation, 2 items, 1943
    - Smiley, Mr. and Mrs. Daniel K., 1 item, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 524)
    - Sparhawk, Frances C., 2 items, 1926 (Box 15, Folder 525)
    - Stevick, Marion (Pratt), 3 items, 1934-35
    - United States Dept. of the Interior, 2 items, 1935 (Box 15, Folder 526)
    - University of Oklahoma Press, 7 items, 1940-41 (Box 15, Folder 527)
    - Warner, Glenn S., 1 item, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 528)
    - Wells, Nana Stevick, 2 items, 1955
    - Yale University Library, 1 item, 1955 (Box 15, Folder 529)
    - Miscellaneous, 10 items, 1919-35, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 530)
  - ANNA LAURA PRATT
    - Agnew, Mary N., 1 item, 1901 (Box 15, Folder 531)
    - Burke, Charles H., 3 items, 1924-25
    - Dawes, Anna L.,2 items, 1896 (Box 15, Folder 532)
    - George H. Doran Co., 1 item, 1926
    - Francis, Mr. and Mrs. John, Jr., 3 items, 1917, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 533)
    - Halbert, Elizabeth L., 1 item, 1904
    - Harper and Brothers, 1 item, 1895 (Box 15, Folder 534)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1889 (Box 15, Folder 535)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 536)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 537)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 538)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 539)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 540)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1890 (Box 15, Folder 541)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1890 (Box 16, Folder 542)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 2 items, 1890, 1895 (Box 16, Folder 543)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 6 items, 1901-04 (Box 16, Folder 544)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1906, 1908 (Box 16, Folder 545)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 3 items, 1909 (Box 16, Folder 546)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 6 items, 1910-11 (Box 16, Folder 547)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 4 items, 1912 (Box 16, Folder 548)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 5 items, 1913 (Box 16, Folder 549)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 8 items, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 550)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 7 items, 1914 (Box 16, Folder 551)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1915 (Box 16, Folder 552)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 8 items, 1916 (Box 16, Folder 553)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 4 items, 1917 (Box 16, Folder 554)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 7 items, 1918 (Box 16, Folder 555)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 3 items, 1919 (Box 16, Folder 556)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 6 items, 1920 (Box 16, Folder 557)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 3 items, 1921 (Box 16, Folder 558)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 5 items, 1922 (Box 16, Folder 559)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 11 items, 1923 (Box 16, Folder 560)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1924, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 561)
    - Hines, John L., 2 items, 1924 (Box 16, Folder 562)
    - Kelly, Clyde, 1 item, 1924
    - Larocque, Annie S., 1 item, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 563)
    - J. F. Manning Co., 1 item, 1927
    - [Mason], Eunice, 2 items, 1903 (Box 17, Folder 564)
    - [Mason], Will and Nana, 1 item, 1871
    - Mather, S. A., 1 item, [1882?] (Box 17, Folder 565)
    - Paisano, Mary and William, 1 item, 1917
    - Pendleton, David, 1 item, 1879 (Box 17, Folder 566)
    - Proctor, Edna Dean, 3 items, 1903
    - Robitaille, Emily P., 1 item, 1925 (Box 17, Folder 567)
    - Wheelock, Dennison, 3 items, 1894-95
    - Wright, E. W., 1 item, 1862 (Box 17, Folder 568)
  - MASON DELANO PRATT
    - Botsford, Della F., 1 item, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 569)
    - Brunhouse, R. L., 2 items, 1933
    - Burgess, Marianna, 2 items, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 570)
    - Chandler, Harry, 1 item, 1924
    - Collier, John, 3 items, 1933, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 571)
    - Dagenet, Emily P., 2 items, 1943
    - Eastman, Elaine Goodale, 3 items, 1934 (Box 17, Folder 572)
    - Florida prisoners (correspondence relating to), 32 items, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 572a)
    - Gardner, Walter M., 2 items, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 573)
    - Hawkins, Edgar M., 1 item, 1924 (Box 17, Folder 574)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 7 items, 1933, 1942-44
    - Hepburn, Andrew H., 1 item, 1942 (Box 17, Folder 575)
    - Holt, Rackham, 1 item, 1942
    - Lipps, O. H., 2 items, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 576)
    - Nat'l Cyclopedia of American Biography, 2 items, 1933
    - Nye, Col. W. S., 1 item, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 577)
    - Paul, William L., 1 item, 1943
    - Peele, Mrs. S. J.?, 1 item, 1945 (Box 17, Folder 578)
    - Pettinos, George F., 1 item, 1943
    - Pratt, Richard H., II, 5 items, 1937, 1942-43 (Box 17, Folder 579)
    - Roosevelt, Franklin D., 2 items, 1933 (Box 17, Folder 580)
    - Saturday Evening Post, 2 items, 1939
    - Sickles, C. M., 1 item, 1943 (Box 17, Folder 581)
    - Stevick, Marion (Pratt), 1 item, 1933
    - Tousey, Col. Thomas G., 2 items, 1938
  - RICHARD HENRY PRATT
    - Hawkins, Edgar M., 18 items, 1906-23 (Box 17, Folder 582)
    - Hawkins family, 9 items, 1908-23 (Box 17, Folder 583)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 12 items, 1886, 1890-92 (Box 17, Folder 584)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 11 items, 1893-99 (Box 17, Folder 585)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 8 items, 1901 (Box 17, Folder 586)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 13 items, 1902 (Box 17, Folder 587)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 7 items, 1904 (Box 17, Folder 588)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 5 items, 1905 (Box 17, Folder 589)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 8 items, 1906 (Box 17, Folder 590)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 3 items, 1907 (Box 17, Folder 591)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 8 items, 1908 (Box 17, Folder 592)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1909 (Box 17, Folder 593)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 7 items, 1910 (Box 17, Folder 594)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1911 (Box 17, Folder 595)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 8 items, 1912 (Box 17, Folder 596)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1913 (Box 17, Folder 597)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 12 items, 1914 (Box 17, Folder 598)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1915 (Box 17, Folder 599)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 7 items, 1916 (Box 17, Folder 600)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 9 items, 1917 (Box 17, Folder 601)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 12 items, 1918 (Box 17, Folder 602)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 12 items, 1919 (Box 17, Folder 603)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 5 items, 1920 (Box 18, Folder 604)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 6 items, 1921 (Box 18, Folder 605)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 10 items, 1922 (Box 18, Folder 606)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 27 items, 1923, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 607)
    - McCombs, Bobby, 2 items, 1922 (Box 18, Folder 608)
    - McCombs, Ellenor and Robert S., 11 items, 1922-23
    - Pratt, A. Laura (Mason), 3 items, 1864 (Box 18, Folder 609)
    - Pratt, A. Laura (Mason), 2 items, 1868, 1870 (Box 18, Folder 610)
    - Pratt, A. Laura (Mason), 9 items, 1874 (Box 18, Folder 611)
    - Pratt, A. Laura (Mason), 6 items, 1878 (Box 18, Folder 612)
    - Pratt, A. Laura (Mason), 12 items, 1879 (Box 18, Folder 613)
    - Pratt, A. Laura (Mason), 10 items, 1883-87 (Box 18, Folder 614)
    - Pratt, A. Laura (Mason), 5 items, 1892-1917, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 615)
    - Pratt, Jennie E., 2 items, 1901, 1918 (Box 18, Folder 616)
    - Pratt, Mabel, 2 items, 1919, n.d.
    - Pratt, Mason D., 14 items, 1878, 1918-19 (Box 18, Folder 617)
    - Pratt, Mason D., 11 items, 1920, 1922-23 (Box 18, Folder 618)
    - Pratt, Richard, H., II, 10 items, 1917-23 (Box 18, Folder 619)
    - Pratt, Richenda, 1 item, 1890 (Box 18, Folder 620)
    - Pratt, Sarah (Sally), 6 items, 1919-23 (Box 18, Folder 621)
    - Pratt, Seth B., 1 item, 1883
    - Stevick, Dorothy, 5 items, 1920, 1922 (Box 18, Folder 622)
    - Stevick, Guy LeRoy, 10 items, 1903-19 (Box 18, Folder 623)
    - Stevick, Guy LeRoy, 13 items, 1922-23 (Box 18, Folder 624)
    - Stevick, Marion (Pratt), 14 items, 1919-23, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 625)
    - Stevick, Mary E., 8 items, 1918-23 (Box 18, Folder 626)
    - Stevick, Roy, 11 items, 1918-19 (Box 18, Folder 627)
    - Stevick family, 12 items, 1922-23, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 628)
    - Unidentified, 9 items, 1901-23, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 629)
  - RICHARD HENRY PRATT, II
    - Brewster, W., 1 item, 1927 (Box 18, Folder 630)
    - Gansworth, Leander N., 2 items, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 631)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 3 items, 1936, 1955
    - Lipps, Oscar H., 1 item, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 632)
    - Pettinos, George F., 1 item, 1943
    - Pratt, Mason D., 1 item, 1943? (Box 18, Folder 633)
    - Rogers, Edward L., 2 items, 1943
    - United States Dept. of the Interior, 1 item, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 634)
  - SARAH PRATT
    - Sisson, Edgar, 1 item, 1931 (Box 18, Folder 635)
  - GUY LeROY STEVICK
    - Chandler, Harry, 1 item, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 636)
    - Collier, Robert, 1 item, 1914
    - Eastman, Elaine Goodale, 4 items, 1934 (Box 18, Folder 637)
    - Harper, Bessie C., 1 item, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 638)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1924
    - Stevick, Marion (Pratt), 2 items, 1888 (Box 18, Folder 639)
    - United States Dept. of the Interior, 1 item, 1929
  - MARION PRATT STEVICK
    - Dagenett, Emily P., 1 item, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 640)
    - Eastman, Elaine Goodale, 1 item, n.d.
    - Frysinger, W. Maslin, 1 item, 1923 (Box 18, Folder 641)
    - Hawkins, Nana (Pratt), 1 item, 1934
    - Leussler, Harrison, 1 item, 1928 (Box 18, Folder 642)
    - Paul, William L., 1 item, 1897
    - Pratt, Mason D., 1 item, 1943 (Box 18, Folder 643)
    - Seabrook, Alice M., 1 item, 1920
    - Standing Bear, Chief, 2 items, 1929, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 644)
    - Stevick, Roy, 1 item, 1918
    - Wilbur, Ray Lyman, 1 item, 1929 (Box 18, Folder 645)
- Addresses, Diaries, Writings, and Notes, 1862-1953; Series III; (4 boxes)
  This series contains addresses, articles, and notes written by Pratt. In addition there is a diary kept by Pratt during the Civil War and several versions of an autobiographical work that Pratt wrote in his later years. Two drafts of this manuscript are filed under Pratt's working title, The Indian No Problem. Fragments of a later version with a foreword and conclusion written by Pratt's widow are filed under her title, Indian Trails. A revised and edited version of Pratt's manuscript was published in 1964 under the title Battlefield and Classroom. A galley proof of this manuscript is also included in this series. Addresses given by Pratt are arranged in chronological order. Title or subject is noted along with place of delivery if known. Copies of nine articles by Pratt are also included in this series. Not all of these reminiscences or statements were written for publication. Finally, there are several folders of miscellaneous notes and writings by members of Pratt's family.
  - ADDRESSES
    - Civilizing the Indian, 1 item, 1879? (Box 19, Folder 646)
    - Indian civilization, before the Nat'l Educ. Convention, 1 item, 1883 (Box 19, Folder 647)
    - Purpose of Sioux Commission, before the General Council of Sioux, 1 item, 1888 (Box 19, Folder 648)
    - Civilizing the Indian, before Protestant ministers, 1 item, 1891 (Box 19, Folder 649)
    - Breaking away from the reservation, before Carlisle students, 1 item, 1894 (Box 19, Folder 650)
    - Civil service and public education, before the Cumberland County Teacher's Association, 1 item, 1897 (Box 19, Folder 651)
    - Civil service, before Senate Committee (with printed copy of actual testimony), 2 items, 1897 (Box 19, Folder 652)
    - Civilizing the Indian, before Baptists, 1 item, 1904 (Box 19, Folder 653)
    - Pratt's retirement, before Carlisle students?, 1 item, 1904? (Box 19, Folder 654)
    - "The Indian No Problem," before the Philadelphia women's club, 1 item, 1904? (Box 19, Folder 655)
    - Freedom and responsibility, before the Miss Wolcott School, 1 item, 1905 (Box 19, Folder 656)
    - Abraham Lincoln, before the Colorado Commandery of the Loyal Legion, 1 item, 1906 (Box 19, Folder 657)
    - Equality for minorities, before the Second Presbyterian Church of Carlisle, Pennsylvania, 1 item, 1906 (Box 19, Folder 658)
    - Civilizing the Indian, before the Good Citizenship Convention, 1 item, 1910 (Box 19, Folder 659)
    - The Negro and slavery, before a "colored" audience in Philadelphia, 2 items, 1911 (Box 19, Folder 660)
    - "The Fathers of the Republic on Indian Transformation and Redemption," before the Society of American Indians, 1 item, 1913 February (Box 19, Folder 661)
    - "Indian Schools--an Exposure," before the Ladies Missionary Society, 1 item, 1914? (Box 19, Folder 662)
    - "Our Forlorn Indians," before the Lake Mohonk Conference, 1 item, 1915? (Box 19, Folder 663)
    - "Synopsis of Several Addresses on Indians at Pasadena, Los Angeles, and Redlands, California," 1 item, 1916 (Box 19, Folder 664)
    - "Talk before Northern California Indian Association," 1 item, 1916 (Box 19, Folder 665)
    - "The Place and Destiny of the Indian in the Nation's Life," before a California audience, 1 item, 1916? (Box 19, Folder 666)
    - "To the 1921 Graduating Class of the Riverside School," 1 item (Box 19, Folder 667)
    - Civilizing the Indian, 2 items (Box 19, Folder 668)
    - Civilizing the Indian, before the California Indian Association, 1 item (Box 19, Folder 669)
    - Civilizing the Indian, before the Presbyterian Assembly, 1 item (Box 19, Folder 670)
    - Equality for minorities, 2 items, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 671)
    - Indian dance, before Author's Club, Rochester, N.Y., 2 items (Box 19, Folder 672)
  - ARTICLES
    - "Against Further Bureauizing the Indians," 1 item, 1904 (Box 19, Folder 673)
    - "Executing the Indian Whiskey Law," 1 item (Box 19, Folder 674)
    - "The First Comanche School," 4 items, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 675)
    - "The Florida Indian Prisoners of 1875 to 1878," 2 items (Box 19, Folder 676)
    - "An Indian Dance," 1 item (Box 19, Folder 677)
    - "Indian Promptness," 1 item (Box 19, Folder 678)
    - Interview with R. H. Pratt, 1 item, 1896 (Box 19, Folder 679)
    - "Some Experiences with Our Most Nomadic Indians," 2 items (Box 19, Folder 680)
    - R. H. Pratt's annotations on a speech of E. B. Merritt, 3 items, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 681)
  - DIARIES
    - Record of expeditions, 1 item, 1873-74 (Box 19, Folder 682)